thehonestkitchen.com 2019-05-24

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Your privacy and the privacy of all visitors to the TheHonestKitchen.com Web Site (the “Web Site”) are very important to us. The Honest Kitchen has adopted the following Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of your personal information. The Policy discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our Web Site:

WE WILL NOT USE YOUR INFORMATION FOR ANY PURPOSE THAT YOU HAVE NOT EXPRESSLY AUTHORIZED. YOUR EMAIL ADDRESS AND CONTACT INFORMATION WILL NOT BE SOLD, RENTED, OR SHARED WITH OTHER ORGANIZATIONS FOR COMMERCIAL PURPOSES OR IN WAYS DIFFERENT THAN WHAT IS DISCLOSED IN THIS POLICY.

###### Notice of information collected and disclosed

This Policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you through our Web Site, how we may use or disclose that information, and our efforts to protect it.

Our Web Site does track certain information about the visits to our Web Site. For example, we compile statistics that show the numbers and frequency of visitors to our Web Site and its individual pages. These aggregated statistics are used internally to improve our Web Site and for product development and marketing purposes generally. Those aggregated statistics may also be provided to advertisers and other third parties, but again, the statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information. For example, we request information from you when you:

  * Log-on to certain areas of our Web Site, where you are prompted to provide us with your Login and password as a condition to gaining access to certain information, materials or services.
  * Subscribe to a newsletter or desire to be added to our mailing lists for other products or services.
  * Place an order.
  * Participate in a sweepstakes or other promotional offer.
  * Provide feedback in an online survey.

In connection with your use of our Web Site, we may collect the following information:

  * The domain name of visitors to our Web Site.
  * The e-mail addresses of users who establish an account with us or request our newsletter.
  * Aggregate information on what pages on our Web Site users access or visit.
  * Information volunteered by the user, such as product purchases, site registration and e-mail update requests.
  * Information about your transactions with us or others, including, without limitation, credit card information.

We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we’ll use this information to contact you.

We are the sole owners of the information collected on the Web Site. We use the personal identifying information you voluntarily provide to register you as a user of the Web Site, to administer Web Site usage and monitor traffic-levels, and to contact you regarding your reason for visiting the Web Site and to ask you about improvements we can make to our Web Site and our services, if necessary. We also may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Web Site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Unless you ask us not to, we may use your e-mail address to contact you directly regarding specials, services, products or information that we believe interest you.

From time to time, we may also disclose information to fulfill certain legal and regulatory requirements or if we believe, in good faith, that such disclosure is legally required or necessary to protect others’ rights or to prevent harm.

We partner with other third party companies to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

As part of our commitment to quality customer service, occasional communications may be sent on behalf of The Honest Kitchen, by an independent third party ratings and review service. Active, regular customers’ anonymous email addresses will be used by this service one time only, for the express purpose of independently evaluating our processes, including The Honest Kitchen’s general service, courtesy, selling, and shipping of actual orders placed, and will not be owned, shared or used for any other purpose by the third party. No financial or other information will be shared with the third party. You may opt out of these review emails at any time.

Any non-personal information, communications and material you send to this site or to us by e-mail are on a non-confidential basis. We are free to use and reproduce any such information freely, and for any purpose whatsoever. Specifically, we will be free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques contained in such information for any purpose, including developing, manufacturing or marketing products. Any information you send to this site must be truthful, not violate the rights of others and be legal.

###### Opting-Out

You may choose to restrict our use of your information. If you are a user of our Web Site or services, you may restrict distribution of your information by contacting us via the email address or phone number given on our website and indicating such restrictions.

If you receive communications from us that you do not want to receive, you can opt-out from receiving these communications by specifically telling us to stop sending them to you.

You may also “opt-out” entirely from providing personal information to us by not registering on our Web Site. You may also choose at a later date to:

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

Please note, certain sections of our Web Site do require registration in order to use these sections and services. If you choose not to register or provide certain information, these sections will not be available for your use.We will not use your information for any purpose other than for those purposes you have authorized and we will not use your information for a purpose that is incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally authorized by you. We will treat as sensitive any information that we receive from a third party where the third party treats and identifies it as sensitive.

###### Onward transfer (transfers to third parties)

We will apply the “Notice of Information Collected and Disclosed” and “Opt-Out” policies discussed above in the event we propose to disclose your information to a third party. If we propose to disclose your information to a third party that is acting as our agent or on our behalf, we will ensure that the third party has agreed to assure adequate protection of your information.

###### Security

For your security, Account access on our Web Site may be encrypted with Secure Sockets Layer Protocol (“SSL”) technology on both the client and server end by selecting the secure server option when prompted to do so. This Web Site takes every reasonable precaution to protect our users’ information. Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the web page. We are a PCI compliant company, meaning that we follow The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) – a set of requirements designed to ensure that all companies that process, store or transmit credit card information maintain a secure environment.

When users submit sensitive information via the Web Site, your information is protected both online and off-line. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

Please note that e-mail may not be encrypted and cannot be considered a secure means of transmitting sensitive information. We will never ask you to submit your financial data, such as your credit card account numbers, via e-mail.

Your account containing your information is password protected. Only those who log on with your password can access your account. We have taken appropriate security measures to protect your personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. However, please remember that you play a valuable part in security as well. Your password to access your account should never be shared with anyone. After you have finished using the Web Site, you should log off and exit your browser so no unauthorized persons can use our Web Site with your name and account information. Furthermore, if you provide any information to parties who operate web sites that are linked to or from our Web Site, different rules may apply to their collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of such other sites before revealing any sensitive or personal information. Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the ultimate security of any information you transmit.

###### Data Integrity

We make every effort to ensure that your information is reliable for the use you intend, and that it is accurate, complete, and current. To assist us in ensuring that your information is relevant on an on-going basis for its intended purposes, we encourage you to update your information as frequently as is necessary. We may periodically send you a notice asking you to update your information.

###### Cookies

A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your computer’s hard drive when you visit those sites. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that a web site uses to track the pages you have visited. When you register at the Web Site, we may use a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We do not store passwords or any personal information about you. We may use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track information while you are on our Web Site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Cookies also enable you to enter the Web Site as a registered user without having to log on each time.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use the Web Site. However, if you turn off cookies, then you may not be able to utilize certain features of the Web Site.

###### Opting-Out

A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your computer’s hard drive when you visit those sites. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that a web site uses to track the pages you have visited. When you register at the Web Site, we may use a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We do not store passwords or any personal information about you. We may use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track information while you are on our Web Site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Cookies also enable you to enter the Web Site as a registered user without having to log on each time.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use the Web Site. However, if you turn off cookies, then you may not be able to utilize certain features of the Web Site.

###### Children's Privacy

We are concerned about the safety of children and their use of the Internet. The Web Site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 13. If we receive actual knowledge that we have received such personal information without the required verifiable parental consent, we will delete the information from our database as soon as we practicably can.

###### Effective date and future changes

This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 2013. We may occasionally change this Privacy Policy. If we do, we will post the changes on the Web Site and the changes will take effect as soon as posted. If we change our information practices in the future, we will post the changes to our Web Site to notify you and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web Site periodically.

###### Application of this notice

This Notice applies only to the information collected by us from the users of our Web Site. It does not apply to information collected by us in any other way, including offline.

###### Contact Information

Please read this Policy carefully and feel free to contact us by sending us a message by [**clicking here**](mailto:questions@thehonestkitchen.com). You can also contact us by telephone at (866) 437-9729 if you have any inquiries, complaints or questions regarding its contents.
